Mita!
三田小姐
My wife didn't die in an accident.
我太太不是死於意外
She committed suicide.
她是自殺的
She died because of me.
她是因為我才會死的
Good morning.
早安
Excuse me, Mita.
三田小姐
I'm sorry,
不好意思
but could you not tell the kids
我昨天說的事
what I told you yesterday?
可以請妳別跟孩子們說嗎？
Everyone thinks that their mother just drowned in the river.
他們都以為媽媽是在河裡溺死
They would be shocked if they knew she killed herself,
要是發現她是自殺，會很震驚
and I wouldn't know what to do.
我會不知道該怎麼辦
Of course, I know that eventually…
我知道等時候到了…
Or rather, I know I should tell them soon.
應該說我會盡快跟他們說
I'll tell them myself.
我會親自跟他們說
As you wish.
沒問題
Good morning.
早安
Today is for incombustible trash.
今天是收可燃垃圾
You made a mistake the other day.
你前幾天搞錯了
Sorry about that.
不好意思
Good morning.
早安
Man!
爽啊
It feels great to release it all early in the morning!
早上大解放感覺真好
Good morning.
早安
Kakeru. Remember I told you to stop doing this?
小翔，我不是說過不能這樣喝嗎？
Seriously, stop nagging at everything!
別唸東唸西了
-Here you go. -Right…
-請用 -好
Oh, thanks.
謝謝
Why are you admiring her?
幹嘛盯著她看？
Stupid! What are you saying?
傻瓜，在亂說什麼啊？
I told you not to hit my head!
我說了別打我的頭
Hey, good morning.
嘿，早安
-Morning.
-早安
Look, Daddy!
爸爸，你看
-What is it? -Kii!
-希衣 -什麼？
I'm going to put all my treasures here,
我的寶貝都要放在這裡
together with the stones I gave Mom.
裡面有我給媽媽的石頭
There's the photo that Yui took,
這是姐拍的照片
and the card that Kaito wrote.
海斗寫的卡片
Also, the origami that I made with Mom!
這是我跟媽做的紙鶴
-Hey, Dad. -Yes?
-爸 -是？
Why was Mom at the river that day?
媽那天怎麼會到河邊？
She always told us not to go there
她總是告訴我們別去
since the river current is fast and it's dangerous.
因為水流很快，很危險
Besides, Mom never knew how to swim.
而且媽不會游泳
Right…
對
You're right.
是啊
That does seem strange.
是有點奇怪
Breakfast is ready.
早餐準備好了
-It looks like hotel breakfast. -Here is today's news.
-好像飯店早餐 -歡迎收看今日新聞
I'm digging in.
我開動了
Yesterday, an elementary student committed suicide due to bullying.
一位小學生在昨天因霸凌而自殺
The school acknowledged
學校承認
-the bullying case, and apologized. -Kaito. You're not being bullied, are you?
-有霸凌情形，並公開道歉 -海斗，你沒被霸凌吧？
Of course not.
當然沒有
It is also said that the bullies threw his bag around.
據聞霸凌的同學亂丟他的書包
Everyone, listen to me.
大家，我有事要說
What's bullying, Daddy?
爸爸，霸凌是什麼？
Oh, it means…
喔，意思是…
How should I explain it?
該怎麼解釋呢？
Yui.
小結
Stop throwing these questions at me!
少拿這種問題來問我
Listen.
那個
Bullying means
霸凌就是
you play pranks on your friends and make them cry.
惡整朋友，把他們弄哭
Why would you do that?
怎麼會有人這樣？
What? That's, well…
這個…
Mita! Why do people bully others?
三田小姐！ 為什麼會有人霸凌別人？
That is because…
那是因為…
humans are weak creatures.
人類是脆弱的生物
If someone is weaker than them, they beat that person down.
看到弱者，就要打壓對方
And if someone is stronger than them, they get scared and run off.
看到強者，就落荒而逃
That is the true nature of humans.
這就是人類的本性
Mita.
三田小姐
You didn't have to say it that way.
不用說成這樣吧
If there is nothing else, I will take the trash out now.
沒別的事的話，我去倒垃圾
Oh, sure. Thanks.
好，謝謝
Hey.
嘿
Don't you think that lady is really weird?
不覺得那阿姨很奇怪嗎？
She doesn't smile at all, and I don't even know what she's thinking.
她完全不笑，也不知道她在想什麼
When she looks at me with those eyes,
她看我的眼神
it feels like she can see what I'm thinking.
好像能看穿我在想什麼
Why is she a housekeeper in the first place?
她怎麼會來當家政婦？
Is she not married? Does she have no kids?
她沒結婚，也沒小孩嗎？
Hey, Dad. Do you know anything about her?
爸，你知道她的背景嗎？
Not really.
不太清楚
But…
不過…
The housekeeping agency told me something.
家政婦介紹所的人說了件事
What is it?
什麼事？
She said that Mita will do anything we ask,
她說要三田做什麼都行
so we should be careful about that.
所以我們要小心
What? What does that mean?
咦？這是什麼意思？
So in an extreme case…
最極端的情況是…
If you ask her to kill someone,
就算叫她去殺人
she will do it.
她也會照做
No way…
不會吧
She's really bad news!
這不太妙吧
She also burned Mom's belongings the other day, too.
她昨天也燒了媽的東西
Hey. Don't you think we should know more about her, Dad?
爸，你不覺得我們該多瞭解她嗎？
What? Right…
什麼？是…
You're right.
沒錯
This is good! So good!
這好好吃喔…
-Give me yours. -Will you do everything we ask, Mita?
-你的給我 -三田小姐，要妳做什麼都可以嗎？
If it is something within my means.
我辦得到的話就可以
Then, could you juggle beanbags?
那妳能丟沙包嗎？
As you wish.
沒問題
-You're awesome, Mita! -Oh, wow!
三田小姐，妳好厲害
YOKOHAMA MUNICIPALITY FUJIGAOKA ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
（橫濱市立新藤丘小學）
You stink!
你好臭
You're so smelly!
你臭死了
Why were you even born in the first place?
你怎麼會被生出來啊？
Come on, tell us!
快說啊
-Hey! -Just tell us already!
-喂… -快說啊…
Why do you look so upset?
不開心啊？
I'm counting on you again today, Class President.
班長，今天又要靠你了
What? What do you mean?
什麼？什麼意思？
I mean the test, of course. Make sure to give me all the correct answers again.
考試啊，記得再把答案給我
But it will be bad if the teachers find out.
但讓老師發現就糟了
I think we should stop that today…
今天先不要吧
Don't worry about it. Our teacher is slow to notice it.
別擔心，老師很遲鈍，不會發現的
We'll begin the test now.
要考試了
Put away everything that's on your desk.
桌上的東西收起來
Kai!
小斗
I went grocery shopping with Mita.
我和三田小姐去買菜
Is that so?
是喔？
Welcome back.
歡迎回家
Thanks.
謝謝
Let's go!
走吧
After climbing up this slope
爬上這座山丘之後
There's a tree to the right
往右邊走有一棵樹
Sing with me, Mita.
三田小姐，跟我一起唱
Mom always sings this song for me
我和媽媽走上這斜坡時
when we walk up this slope.
她每次都會唱給我聽
After climbing up
爬上這座
This slope
山丘之後
There's a tree
往右邊走
To the right
有一棵樹
Kai!
小斗
-Mita really can do everything. -What?
-三田小姐真的什麼都辦得到 -什麼？
When she was paying at the cashier,
她在結帳時
she already knew how much the total was before the cashier told her.
不用等收銀員說，她就知道多少錢了
She also remembered all my friends' names at the school!
她還記住了我學校所有朋友的名字
Really?
真的嗎？
Her lunchboxes taste really good, too.
她做的便當也很好吃
Why don't you ask her if you need help?
你有事也可以請她幫忙啊？
What?
什麼？
Oh, okay.
喔，好
Mita. Do you know all the characters in Anpanman?
三田小姐，妳知道 麵包超人的所有角色嗎？
I do.
我知道
Anpanman, Baikinman, Melonpanna, Rollpanna
麵包超人、細菌人 蜜瓜超人、螺旋麵包超人
Creampanda, Tendonman, Katsudonman, Kamameshidon,
奶油麵包小弟、炸蝦飯人 炸豬排人、什錦鍋人
-Omusubiman… -You can stop now, Mita.
-飯糰人… -可以了，三田小姐
What's wrong?
怎麼了嗎？
Oh, sorry. And I even asked you to accompany me.
抱歉，還叫你陪我來
Why did you want to come here?
妳怎麼會想來這裡？
This was where…
這裡是…
my mother drowned.
我媽溺水的地方
I thought that I may find out something if I came here.
我以為來這裡會有發現
For example, how she was feeling back then.
像是她當時的感受
-Hey!
-啊
Oh, my! Yui! What a coincidence! What are you doing out here?
小結，好巧，妳怎麼也在這啊？
You say that, but I'm sure you followed me from school!
妳根本就是從學校跟過來的
Sorry about the other day.
上一次真抱歉
I messed up Kii's birthday party.
我搞砸了希衣的生日派對
Don't worry about it.
沒關係
Help me apologize to them, too.
請幫我跟他們道歉
You know that things always get messy when I'm around.
我去的話又會添麻煩
I won't ever go to your house again.
我不會再去你們家了
See you.
再見
It's fine if you just visit us occasionally.
妳偶爾來找我們沒關係
Really? I can go your house?
真的？我能去你們家嗎？
Just occasionally!
只能偶爾
Thank goodness! I found a place that sells good meat buns.
太好了！我知道一間很好吃的肉包
So I'll buy some for everyone next time! See you!
下次買給你們大家吃，再見
Ozawa, I won't let you off if you do weird things to my cute niece! Bye!
小澤，你要是敢對我可愛的 外甥女亂來就死定了，再見
Kazama.
風間
I would like to ask something about the accounts.
我想問關於帳戶的事
Do you have time?
妳有空嗎？
What is it?
怎麼了？
Please, could we have another proper talk?
拜託，我們能好好談談嗎？
Haven't we talked enough already?
我們談得不夠嗎？
I told you that our only choice is to break up.
我說了唯一的選擇就是分手
So you don't like me at all?
所以妳完全不喜歡我了？
That's not it.
並不是
Your wife…
你太太…
She passed away the day you submitted the divorce papers.
她在你送出離婚文件那天去世
You can't leave your kids, too, right?
你不能也丟下小孩吧？
I'm really sorry,
我真的很抱歉
but there's no way I can be a mother to four children.
但我沒辦法當四個小孩的媽
I understand. But I still like you, Mie--
我瞭解，但我還是很喜歡妳，美枝…
Stop this already.
別這樣
What will you do if the company knows about this?
萬一公司知道怎麼辦？
You're in charge of an important project now, right?
你在負責很重要的案子吧？
Please excuse me.
我先走了
Wait, I…
等等，我…
TO KEIICHI
（惠一收）
I WOULD RATHER DIE THAN BE ABANDONED BY YOU
（我寧可死了，也不想被你拋棄）
Okay. Let's get back.
好，回家吧
This is the Asuda residence.
阿須田家，您好
Oh, hello, Mita?
喂，三田小姐嗎？不好意思
I will be home late today, so I'll have dinner outside.
我今天會晚回家，晚餐會在外面吃
Understood.
好的
Excuse me,
不好意思
but is there anything wrong with the kids' behavior?
孩子最近的表現還正常嗎？
Not at all.
很正常
Would you like to talk to them?
要跟他們說話嗎？
No, it's fine.
沒關係
Well, please apologize to the kids on my behalf.
麻煩幫我跟孩子們道歉
Mr. Asuda will be late tonight.
阿須田先生今天會晚回家
"Please apologize to the kids on my behalf."
“麻煩幫我跟孩子們道歉”
That was his message.
這是他要我傳的話
Got it.
好
Why are you staring at her?
你幹嘛盯著她看？
Are you having dirty thoughts?
在想什麼壞事嗎？
Stop that.
夠了
That's not it!
才不是
Anyway, have you guys realized? The bathroom seems strange.
你們有發現浴室怪怪的嗎？
Strange?
怪怪的？
I was the third one who used it today,
我今天第三個洗澡
Now that you mention it…
聽妳這麼一說
It was clean when I entered, too.
我進去時也很乾淨
Then, when did Mita clean it?
三田小姐是什麼時候打掃的？
Mita can do everything.
三田小姐什麼都會
Will she really do anything…
只要我們開口
if we ask her to?
她真的什麼都會做？
Pretty sure you're having dirty thoughts right now.
你現在才在想壞事吧？
Shut up!
閉嘴
I told you not to hit my head!
我說了不要打我的頭
This is the Asuda residence.
阿須田家，您好
You have a call from your friend, Kaito.
海斗，有朋友找你
What?
什麼？
Who is it?
誰？
He called himself Furuta.
他叫古田
What?
什麼？
"Tell him I'm not around." That's his message for you.
他要我說“跟他說我不在”
Hey! Stop that!
不行這樣講啦
Hello?
喂？
Thanks for the help during the test today, Class President!
班長，謝謝你今天考試幫的忙
Don't mention it… I guess.
不客氣，應該吧
Why don't you come get an air gun with us tomorrow?
明天跟我們一起去買空氣槍吧？
But I don't have money.
但我沒錢
Don't worry. Just go without paying.
沒關係，不用付錢
Are you telling me to shoplift?
你是要我用偷的嗎？
It's harder to get caught when there are more people around.
人多比較不會被抓到
But I have cram school.
但我要去補習
You know what's going to happen if you run away, right?
你要是敢跑走，知道下場會怎樣吧？
Kaito?
海斗？
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
Nothing.
沒事
"Choco, Apple, Lemon,
“巧克力、蘋果、檸檬
and Mochi."
和麻糬
"The four birds grew up gradually and happily."
四隻鳥開心地漸漸長大”
Come in.
請進
It is almost time for me to leave.
我差不多該走了
Is there anything else for me to do?
還有事要吩咐嗎？
Oh, nothing.
沒有
I don't need anything, too.
我也沒有
Please excuse me.
我先告辭了
Mita.
三田小姐
Yes?
是？
Well…
那個…
Will you really do anything I ask?
真的要妳做什麼都可以嗎？
If it is something within my means.
我辦得到就可以
Actually…
那個…
It's about that Furuta who called.
打電話來給我的古田
He always bullies the kids in my class.
他一直欺負班上的同學
Everyone is really bothered by him.
大家都很受不了他
He even asked me to cheat on a test.
他還要我幫他作弊
Just now, he even asked me to go shoplifting.
現在甚至要我去偷東西
If the school knows about this,
要是學校知道了
I won't be able to attend a private school.
我就進不了私立學校了
That guy will never admit he's wrong.
那傢伙死不承認自己有錯
So…
所以…
So?
所以？
Could you
能不能請妳
punish him for me tomorrow?
明天去幫我處罰他？
I learned this in cram school.
我在補習班學到
"To rake someone over the coals." That's what this is, right?
這叫“狠狠教訓一頓”，對吧？
Something like that.
是這樣說吧？
As you wish.
沒問題
Hey, what should we do?
該怎麼辦？
What about this?
這個呢？
-This one? -Okay.
-這個？ -對
-Excuse me. -Yes?
-不好意思 -是？
Can I take a look at the model on that shelf?
我能看架上的那個模型嗎？
Oh, that ship model?
那個模型船嗎？
Give me a moment.
等我一下
Who are you, lady?
阿姨，妳是哪位？
I'm Mita, a housekeeper.
我是家政婦三田
What does a housekeeper want with us?
家政婦找我們幹嘛？
What the hell was that?
搞什麼鬼啊？
That hurt…
好痛…
Hey!
喂
What are you doing to a child?
妳怎麼這樣對小孩？
Let go!
放手
I said let go!
我說了放手
Don't do this!
住手
What?
什麼？
Why did you do that, Mita?
三田小姐，妳怎麼會打人？
Kaito said that Furuta, his classmate,
海斗說古田同學
always bullies the kids in class and they are bothered by him.
一直欺負班上同學，讓大家很受不了
He also threatened him to cheat in class and shoplift.
還逼他考試作弊和偷東西
If this continues, he will never learn his mistakes.
這樣下去他永遠學不乖
So he requested me to "rake him over the coals."
所以他要我“好好教訓他一頓”
Did you really ask her to do that, Kaito?
你真的叫她這樣做嗎，海斗？
I never thought she would really do it.
我以為她不會真的去做
Besides,
而且
it's true that everyone is bothered because of him.
是真的大家都很受不了他
Listen up.
這個
I asked Furuta as well as the other kids,
我問了古田和其他同學
but they said it wasn't true.
他們說這不是真的
On top of that,
而且
they said there's no way they would ask him to cheat or shoplift.
他們說絕對沒有逼他作弊或偷東西
Of course, they would say that!
他們當然會這樣說
Personally,
我自己
I am positive that there is no bullying occurring in the class.
很清楚班級沒有霸凌的情形
You're just pretending that it doesn't exist.
你只是假裝沒有而已
If you really don't know it, you're just plain stupid.
如果真的不知道，那你就是個呆子
Kaito. What do you mean by that?
海斗，你這是什麼意思？
No, I…
不是的
I'm really sorry.
我很抱歉
I'll give him a good scolding when we get home.
我回家會好好罵罵他
I'm truly sorry for the trouble.
抱歉給你添麻煩了
You should apologize, too, Kaito. Stand up.
海斗，你也該道歉，站起來
I heard about it.
我聽說了
First, your youngest daughter inflicted violence on my Tsubasa.
先是你的小女兒對我家小翼動手
Now, your son ordered your housekeeper to punish a classmate.
現在又是你兒子叫家政婦去教訓同學
Just what's wrong with your children?
你的孩子到底出了什麼問題？
Right…
這個…
I'm really sorry.
我很抱歉
Your housekeeper is unbelievable, too.
你的家政婦也很誇張
As long as she's ordered,
只要有人開口
she would set a fire and even abuse children.
她就去放火和打小孩
Knowing a scary person like her lives right next to me
有她這麼恐怖的人住在隔壁
makes it hard for me to sleep at night.
我晚上哪睡得著？
You should fire her immediately. Hear that?
你該馬上把她開除，懂吧？
That's why households with no mothers are so problematic!
家裡沒有母親果然問題一堆
Mr. Asuda.
阿須田先生
Yes?
是？
What is it?
怎麼了？
Should I go ahead and prepare dinner?
我該去準備晚餐了嗎？
That hurt!
好痛
Hey! I told you to stop hitting my head!
我說了別打我的頭
You're the worst!
你爛透了
Why would you ask someone else to punish a classmate?
怎麼會請別人去教訓同學？
You're a man!
你可是男人耶
I understand how you feel, Kaito.
我理解你的苦衷，海斗
But I think you should apologize to your teacher and classmate for now.
但你還是該跟老師和同學道歉
Why do I have to do that?
我幹嘛道歉？
Hey.
喂
What's up with that attitude?
這是什麼態度啊？
Why don't we give it a rest?
先別提這件事了吧？
Kaito knows he's wrong, too.
海斗也知道錯了
Right, Kaito?
對吧，海斗？
I will get the door.
我去開門
Anyway,
而且
why am I in the wrong?
為什麼錯的是我？
Furuta and Mita were the ones in the wrong.
有錯的是古田和三田小姐
Why would she listen to my order?
她怎麼會聽我的話？
You don't usually just beat up a kid!
誰會這樣亂打小孩？
You're right, too.
你說得對
She does seem a little strange.
她感覺是有點奇怪
Is she really fine, Dad?
爸，她真的沒問題嗎？
What?
什麼？
Hey. It will be bad if worse things happen.
要是惹上更大的麻煩就糟糕了
So why don't we replace the housekeeper?
我們換個家政婦吧？
What?
什麼？
Well…
這個嘛…
I guess you're right.
好像也是
No!
不行
I want Mita!
我要三田小姐
I see…
好…
Hey, Keiichi! I heard about Kaito from the lady next door.
姐夫，隔壁太太跟我說了海斗的事
Seems like something bad happened to him!
他好像惹了麻煩
Oh, Urara. Why are you here today?
小麗，妳怎麼會來？
Right. I bought some good meat buns.
我帶了好吃的肉包
But I was careless and I slipped on a puddle.
但我不小心踩到水坑滑倒
On top of that, a bicycle passed by and ran over it.
肉包還被腳踏車輾過去
Anyway, are you all right, Kaito?
算了
You should reflect on your mistakes.
你該好好反省
But I think the one who started the bullying is in the wrong.
但欺負同學的人也有錯
Besides, why didn't you talk to me about it in the first place?
而且你怎麼沒有先跟我說？
Could you leave me alone? You're bothering me.
少煩我好嗎？吵死了
Hey, Kaito.
喂，海斗
You shouldn't say that!
不能這樣說話
It's fine, Keiichi.
沒關係，姐夫
Anyway,
總之
just leave Kaito to me.
海斗的事交給我
-I'll do something about it! -Wait, Urara! That's…
-我會處理的 -等等，小麗，這個…
Don't worry! I'm a teacher, so I'm used to situations like this.
別擔心，我是老師 這種情況我見多了
Also, I caused some trouble to everyone the other day.
而且我上次惹了麻煩
So you could consider this a way for me to make up for that.
這就當作是我賠罪的方式
-Well then! -Wait, Urara!
-拜拜 -等等，小麗
What are you planning to do this time?
妳這次打算要幹嘛？
Jeez! Why does she always come at times like these?
她怎麼每次都這麼會挑時間來？
It's going to get even more complicated now that Urara is involved.
連小麗都扯進來，只會更複雜
Dinner is ready.
晚餐準備好了
That must have been tough for you.
你肯定很辛苦吧？
Oh, right.
對了
I have some good monaka here.
我有好吃的最中餅
They make really good monaka, so have one.
這家很會做，吃一個吧
Thank you.
謝謝
So about Mita…
關於三田小姐的事
She did a really good job with the household chores,
她家事做得非常好
but my neighbor is concerned about her.
但我的鄰居對她有疑慮
Is it possible to replace her?
能不能把她換掉？
I understand. Please give me a moment.
知道了，等我一下
Let's take a look…
我看看
Wait.
等等
Don't you have work today, Mr. Asuda?
阿須田先生，你今天不用上班嗎？
Oh, I have Tuesdays and Wednesdays off. I work in the architectural industry.
我休週二、週三，我是建築業
No way!
不會吧
That's the first time I've heard of it.
我還是第一次聽到
Do you work on the weekends?
你週末要工作嗎？
So you have probably
那你大概
never taken your kids out to play, have you?
沒帶孩子出去玩過吧？
Yes.
對
My wife often complained about that, too.
我太太以前也常抱怨
Here you go.
有了
Is this person fine?
這個人可以嗎？
I see…
是
She's a little old,
她年紀有點大
but she's extremely experienced.
但經驗老道
-I would recommend her. -I see.
-我很推薦她 -好
Okay, that's fine.
好，可以的
I see. Then, I'll tell her to go tomorrow.
好，我請她明天過去
Thank you so much.
感謝
-Well then, please excuse me. -Sure.
-那我先告辭了 -好的…
Excuse me, about Mita…
至於三田小姐那邊…
Don't worry.
沒事的
I'll explain the situation to her.
我會跟她解釋
No, actually…
不，是這樣的…
Excuse me?
你說什麼？
The thing is, my children are quite interested in her.
我的孩子對她很感興趣
She has never smiled,
她從來都不笑
so they wondered what could have happened to her.
所以他們想知道她的故事
I'm sorry.
不好意思
I can't tell you that, since it's a little…
這我無法透露，因為這是…
You mean, it's confidential?
個人隱私？
-Right! That's it. -Yes.
-沒錯… -好
-I see.
-知道了
But…
不過…
That girl…
說到她啊
It's not that she doesn't smile.
她不是不笑
She can't smile.
而是不能笑
She decided that she cannot smile.
她決定自己不能笑
What do you mean by that?
這是什麼意思？
Oh, my!
真是的
I said something unnecessary again. Me and my mouth.
我又多嘴了，真管不住嘴巴
-I'm sorry. Please forget what I said. -Oh, okay.
-抱歉，當我沒說 -好
Huh?
啊？
Hello?
喂？
Mr. Asuda, would you please stop it already?
阿須田先生，該適可而止了吧？
What?
什麼？
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
This is serious.
這很嚴重
Kaito's aunt came to school today.
海斗的阿姨今天到學校來
What?
什麼？
Urara?
小麗？
Attention, everyone!
大家注意
-Sorry everyone. -Who are you?
-各位，不好意思 -妳是誰？
-I'll be done. Could you cooperate? -What's going on?
-很快就好，配合一下好嗎？ -怎麼回事？
It's true that Kaito is in the wrong this time.
這次確實是海斗錯了
But I understand his feelings
但我能理解他的感受
since I'm his aunt!
因為我是他阿姨
Kaito wanted the bullies to stop!
海斗不希望同學被欺負
You guys feel uncomfortable when someone is being bullied too, right?
你們看到有人被欺負也很不好受吧？
You're all in the same class,
你們在同一班
and you're going to graduate in just six months!
再六個月就要畢業了
Let's all get along and make good memories together!
一起好好相處，創造美好的回憶吧
Are you our classmate?
妳是我們的同學嗎？
I mean, when there's bullying in a class,
班上出現霸凌的情形
everyone stops smiling.
大家都笑不出來
Don't you feel sad? Don't you think it's such a shame?
難道不覺得傷心遺憾嗎？
If there's bullying in class,
如果班上有人被欺負
could you tell your homeroom teacher about it?
你們願意跟班導說嗎？
If everyone musters their courage and cooperate,
如果大家鼓起勇氣團結起來
I'm sure that the bullying will stop!
一定能阻止霸凌的人
I want everyone to like each other,
我希望大家相親相愛
not hate each other.
而不是互相討厭
No more anger and crying. I want everyone to always smile!
收起怒氣和淚水 我希望大家笑口常開
Asuda. First was your housekeeper, and now your aunt?
阿須田，先是家政婦 現在又換阿姨來？
-You're the worst. -No, you guys got it wrong.
-你真是爛透了 -你們搞錯了
What's your deal, old hag?
老女人，妳有事嗎？
There's no bullying in this class in the first place.
班上根本就沒人被欺負
Right, everyone?
大家說對吧？
-Go home!
-回家去…
-Hold on, everyone.
-大家，等等
Where are you going, Kaito?
海斗，你要去哪？
Wait for me!
等等我
YOU'RE GROSS DIE, PRETENTIOUS MORON!
（噁心、去死、虛偽的白痴）
Kaito! Where's Urara?
海斗！小麗人呢？
Kaito!
海斗
Come on out, Kai!
小斗，出來啊
I know that what Urara did might have backfired,
我知道小麗的行為可能起了反效果
and it was probably embarrassing.
讓你覺得很丟臉
But she was concerned about you.
但她很關心你
It's my fault, too.
我也有錯
Urara looked really down the other day,
小麗前幾天看起來很傷心
so I said it's fine to come visit us.
所以我說她可以來我們家
Anyway, you better stop this!
總之別再鬧了
I can't get in the room now!
我進不去房間了
Hey!
喂
Kaito!
海斗
Just open the door!
快開門
-I'm leaving. -What? Where are you going?
-我要出門了 -什麼？你要去哪？
Cram school, of course.
去補習班啊
I won't go to school anymore.
我不要再去上學了
-What? -Since it's a public school,
-什麼？ -反正是公立學校
I can graduate even if I miss school.
就算不去上學還是能畢業
I can focus on the exams
我去補習班上課
if I study at cram school.
能專心準備考試
Hey!
喂
Are you serious about that, Kaito?
海斗，你是認真的嗎？
I'm different from you, Kakeru.
小翔，我跟你不一樣
I'm going to enter a private school,
我要上私立學校
and get into a university that is as good as Dad's.
念跟爸爸一樣好的大學
I can't be bothered with all those stupid kids in class.
我沒空理班上的笨蛋
Hey, wait! What do you mean by that?
等一下，你這是什麼意思？
-Hey! -Just forget it for today.
-喂 -今天就先算了
Today, we'll look at question four.
今天要解第四題
This problem involves finding speed.
這題要找出速度
It's from that person.
那個人要給你的
COME TO THE GYM WAREHOUSE AFTER THIS RAT US OUT AND WE'LL KILL YOU
（下課到體育器材室 敢告狀就殺了你）
It was a short while,
雖然相處時間不長
but thank you for everything.
但謝謝你
What?
什麼？
Mr. Asuda has relieved me of my duties.
阿須田先生把我解僱了
You're quitting?
妳要走了？
Yes.
對
Please excuse me.
告辭了
Wait a minute!
等一下
I got into serious trouble because of you!
我因為妳惹上大麻煩
Take responsibility!
妳要負責
What would you like me to do?
你要我怎麼做？
That Furuta said
古田說
he's going to kill me,
他要殺了我
and he's waiting for me in school.
他們在學校等我
Could you kill him for me?
能請妳幫我殺了他嗎？
Guys like him
他這種人
only cause trouble for others while they're alive.
活著只會給別人惹麻煩
It's obvious
沒錯
that he'll commit crimes when he grows up!
他長大一定會犯罪
Why are guys like him alive, while Mom is dead?
他這種人還活著，媽媽卻死了？
Don't you think that's strange?
不覺得很不合理嗎？
Guys like him should die for the sake of this world!
他這種人死了對世界最好
As you wish.
沒問題
No! Why did Mita leave?
不要！為什麼三田小姐走了？
Don't cry, Kii.
希衣，別哭
-No! -Come on.
-不要 -別哭
Welcome home.
歡迎回家
What's wrong, Kii?
希衣，怎麼了？
She's crying because Mita quit.
她因為三田小姐離開哭了
-I don't like this! -Kii got really close to her.
-我不要 -希衣很喜歡她
Go wash your hands now.
去洗手吧
Mita made this for us before she left.
三田小姐離開前煮的
Daddy! Get Mita back here!
爸，叫三田小姐回來
We'll get a new housekeeper tomorrow--
明天會有新的家政婦…
No! I want Mita!
不要，我要三田小姐
Stop crying.
別哭了
Wow, it's so cool.
哇，好酷
That guy is sure taking his time.
那傢伙還真慢
What the heck…
搞什麼？
You again?
又是妳？
What's your deal?
妳想幹嘛？
I'm seriously going to kill you, too!
我也敢殺了妳
What…
幹嘛？
What's wrong with you?
妳有病嗎？
You creep me out! Don't come closer!
妳這怪人，別靠近
Stop coming closer to me!
別靠近我了
Back off!
退後
Stop it…
住手…
Stop!
住手
I'm begging you.
拜託妳
Please stop!
快住手
What will you do if he really dies?
他要是真的死了，妳要怎麼辦？
You might get a death sentence!
妳可能會被判死刑
I don't really care.
我不在乎
Let's go.
走吧
Are you running away?
你要逃跑嗎？
You coward!
膽小鬼
You're the worst,
你爛透了
asking your housekeeper to help again…
又叫家政婦幫忙
You act like a good kid…
假裝是乖小孩
But what you're doing
但你的行為
is exactly the same as what we do!
跟我們的一模一樣
No matter how much you try to run…
你就算逃得再用力
I'll definitely kill you!
我還是會殺了你
What should I do?
我該怎麼辦？
That is…
這…
something you should decide for yourself.
你得自己決定
What will you do?
你打算怎樣？
You weakling!
你這懦夫
Have you ever been hit by someone, Mita?
三田小姐，妳被人打過嗎？
Yes.
被打過
Did it hurt?
會痛嗎？
It hurt.
很痛
But…
不過…
Is it better than…
這跟逃跑比起來
just running away?
有比較好嗎？
What?
怎樣？
Just what can you do?
你敢過來嗎？
What's your deal?
你想怎樣？
Why do you bully the other kids?
你為什麼要欺負別人？
Why do you hurt our classmates?
你為什麼要傷害同學？
What will you do if that person dies?
要是同學死了怎麼辦？
No matter how sorry you are,
你說再多抱歉
you can never see them again!
都再也看不到對方了
No matter how much you regret it,
不管你多後悔
you can never make up for your sins!
都沒辦法彌補過錯
It's a really big deal when someone dies!
人死掉可是件大事
You get so sad, so hurt, and so angry…
你會很傷心、痛苦、難過
That disgusting feeling will stay with you forever!
這難受的感覺會跟著你一輩子
Do you even understand it?
你懂不懂啊？
Do you understand that?
你懂嗎？
What's wrong with you guys?
你們有什麼毛病？
I'm the worst.
我爛透了
Personally…
我認為…
I believe you did great.
你做得很好
I understand.
知道了
Thank you so much.
感謝妳
Well then, please excuse me.
好，我先告辭了
Dad.
爸
Please don't let Mita quit.
拜託別讓三田小姐離開
The one at fault…
有錯的…
is me.
是我
It's all my fault.
全都是我的錯
Daddy.
爸爸
Well…
這…
What? Mita?
什麼？三田小姐？
You have a visitor.
有人找你
What?
什麼？
What? Father-in-law?
岳父？
I heard about it.
我聽說了
That housekeeper…
那個家政婦
She inflicted violence on children!
她對小孩施暴
-Stop it, Dad! -You keep quiet!
-爸，別說了 -妳別說話
How dare you sneak into someone's school and embarrass yourself!
妳居然偷跑去別人的學校丟人現眼
Aren't you ashamed as an educator?
妳身為老師不覺得丟臉嗎？
I told you that I'm reflecting!
我說了我在反省了
Hey.
嘿
Why is Kaito injured now?
為什麼海斗也受傷了？
Did you do this, too?
也是妳幹的嗎？
Oh, you got it wrong, Father-in-law.
不是這樣的，岳父
Are you aware
你清楚
of your responsibilities as a father?
自己身為父親的責任嗎？
Why did you let a woman like her into the house?
怎麼會讓家裡出現這種女人？
Nagiko is already gone.
止子已經走了
Are you going to turn this house into a complete mess?
你要讓這一家亂成一團嗎？
Fire that housekeeper now!
馬上把那個家政婦開除
I will not let Mita quit.
我不會開除三田小姐
What?
什麼？
If anything happens to this family,
如果家裡出了問題
I will take full responsibility as the father.
我這個父親會負全責
Grandpa.
外公
It's sleep time for Kii already.
希衣該上床睡覺了
I'm sorry, everyone. Come on, Dad. Let's go.
不好意思
I can tell.
我很清楚
You have no right to be their father!
你沒資格當他們父親
I will expose your true nature.
我會揭穿你的真面目
Just give it a break already, Dad!
爸，說夠了吧？
Come on, let's go!
走了啦
Oh, no!
糟糕
I'm leaving!
我要出門了
Me, too!
我也是
-I'm leaving! -Have a safe trip.
-我出門了 -路上小心
Have a safe trip!
路上小心
I'm leaving.
我要出門了
Okay.
好
Have a safe trip.
路上小心
I'm leaving.
我出門了
I WOULD RATHER DIE THAN BE ABANDONED BY YOU
（我寧可死了，也不想被你拋棄）
DIVORCE REGISTRATION
（離婚協議書）
Mr. Asuda. You should leave for work soon.
主人，你差不多該出門了
Oh, okay.
好
Mita!
三田小姐
I have a favor to ask.
我有事要請妳幫忙
What is it?
什麼事？
This letter…
這封信…
Could you burn it?
能請妳燒掉嗎？
You may think I'm a coward…
妳可能會覺得我很懦弱
But I've decided
但我決定
that I won't talk about what happened to my wife to the kids.
不要跟孩子們講我太太的事
When I think about how shocked they would be
我一想到如果他們知道
when they find out their mother committed suicide,
媽媽是自殺的，會有多震驚
I think keeping it a secret
就覺得別說出來
would be better for them.
對他們比較好
I understand.
知道了
Stop!
住手
Yui?
小結？
What did you just say, Dad?
爸，你剛剛說了什麼？
You… Why are you here?
妳怎麼會在這？
What did you say?
你說了什麼？
You chose your mistress over us!
你為了第三者選擇拋下我們
What do you think we should do?
我們該怎麼辦？
I do not have the right to comment on other people's lives.
我沒資格對別人的人生發表意見
-Could you expose everything he did? -As you wish.
-妳能揭發他外遇的事嗎？ -沒問題
Keiichi Asuda is having an affair since last year…
阿須田惠一從去年開始外遇
-Stop it, Mita! -Because of that…
-三田小姐，夠了 -因為這樣…
She went through a lot of things when she was younger.
她年輕時經歷過很多事
Could you bathe with me today?
今天能陪我泡澡嗎？
As you wish.
沒問題
Shut up!
閉嘴
Don't hit Daddy!
別打爸爸
Mita…
三田小姐
Help me.
幫幫我